<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://graceponders.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://graceponders.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-01-18T20:31:11+00:00</updated><id>https://graceponders.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Mt Ballow</title><link href="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/ballow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mt Ballow"/><published>2025-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/ballow</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/ballow/"><![CDATA[<p>PSA: when Ollie says “you’ll be fine in shorts,” he’s lying. I came out of this hike looking like I’d lost a fight with a barbed wire fence. Wear the damn pants.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/log.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>It was good on paper: Ollie and Rhett were hunting for range-restricted mountain endemics, and I was hunting for a pretty mountaintop where I could read my book in peace. We all technically got what we wanted, I suppose.</p> <p>What we also got was mauled by solanum and attacked by stinging trees in 30 degrees and 100 percent humidity.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/nothofagus.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>The Nothofagus stand at the top made it worth our while, but I did decide to hike down wearing my sleeping thermals.</p> <p>Might stick to the beaten track for the next little while…</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="gracewanders"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[PSA: when Ollie says “you’ll be fine in shorts,” he’s lying. I came out of this hike looking like I’d lost a fight with a barbed wire fence. Wear the damn pants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wild South Coast Way</title><link href="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/wild-south-coast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wild South Coast Way"/><published>2025-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/wild%20south%20coast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/wild-south-coast/"><![CDATA[<p>I don’t think there are many things more humbling than hiking with a 2-time marathon runner. It definitely helps if they’re a coolawesomeamazingsmartbeautiful woman though.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/oak2.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>On our way to a conference in Adelaide, Oak and I decided to hike the Wild South Coast Way on the Heysen Trail, a 75km stretch of (supposedly) relaxing rugged coastline. It turned out to be quite a lot steeper than we’d anticipated, and I managed to get lost twice, but it was still one of the most seamless hikes either of us has done.</p> <p>The campgrounds were incredible. The views were gorgeous. We don’t need to talk about the endless cow paddocks on the third day. I’ve mostly erased them from my memory anyway.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/oak.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>We saw shinglebacks and western greys and echidnas. We talked about ethics and boyfriends and sustainability, and I learned about r/hikervoguetrash and Dungeon Crawler Carl. Oak is a tech wizard (and also just generally brilliant), and this website was her idea, so if you’re reading this please say “thank you Oak”.</p> <p>I think we both had low expectations going into this hike. Our original plans for Flinders Ranges and Kangaroo Island had been thwarted by exclusionary $600 buses, so we weren’t exactly optimistic. But we were both genuinely impressed with this trail. Most of these hikes I’d consider Type II fun, but this was a legitimately awesome trail and deserves way more hype.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/vgrace.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="gracewanders"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t think there are many things more humbling than hiking with a 2-time marathon runner. It definitely helps if they’re a coolawesomeamazingsmartbeautiful woman though.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cooloola Great Walk</title><link href="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/cooloola/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cooloola Great Walk"/><published>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/cooloola</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/cooloola/"><![CDATA[<p>I don’t think it gets much better than this.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/grace.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>Cooloola was my first solo multiday hike, and it was one of the best things I’ve ever done.</p> <p>Ollie dropped me at the northern entrance in Rainbow Beach, which meant I had slightly more downhill than uphill on my walk back to the Noosa North Shore ferry where I’d left my car. I did find him in a tree around the 8km mark, not entirely assured that I wasn’t going to die alone in the bush. He walked me to the Lake Poona picnic area, ate half my lunch, and disappeared.</p> <p>Love of my life.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/heath.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>The next four days were physically brutal but mentally fantastic. Skipping the second campsite to do 35km on the second day was potentially not my brightest idea. I earned some very impressive blisters (the keen reader will pick up that I blister instantly and have not found a solution yet), and I really enjoyed being alone, but I think it’ll be a while before I go solo again. Pretty sure I went a little crazy out there on my own.</p> <p>Easily worth the sore dogs though.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/tent.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="gracewanders"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I don’t think it gets much better than this.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conondale Great Walk</title><link href="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/conondale/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conondale Great Walk"/><published>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/conondale</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2025/conondale/"><![CDATA[<p>When I was 16, we walked a section of the Conondale Great Walk for our grade 12 leadership camp. From memory, we covered about 45km over 3 days, and I had blisters by lunch on the first day.</p> <p>I don’t know what possessed me to attempt this walk again, 7 years later. Maybe the blisters had finally healed. Maybe I thought it would be different this time. (Narrator: it was not different.)</p> <p>56km of pure hillage over 4 days. There were some genuinely awesome views, but also leeches, too little food, and - you guessed it - blisters on the first day. The tracks were overgrown, with plenty of pig damage to keep things interesting.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/boys.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>Not to say I didn’t enjoy this walk, but it certainly wasn’t my favourite. That said, I can wholeheartedly recommend a southwest tofu pie and a bee sting donut from the Kenilworth Bakery on the way home, which almost made the whole thing worth it.</p> <p>Almost.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="gracewanders"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I was 16, we walked a section of the Conondale Great Walk for our grade 12 leadership camp. From memory, we covered about 45km over 3 days, and I had blisters by lunch on the first day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Carnarvon Gorge</title><link href="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2024/carnarvon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Carnarvon Gorge"/><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2024/carnarvon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2024/carnarvon/"><![CDATA[<p>In September 2024, Ollie and I attempted the Carnarvon Great Walk (key word: attempted).</p> <p>This is an 87km loop with some notoriously steep sections. We were woefully unprepared, hauling a whopping 4 cans of beans, 6 cans of tuna (don’t ask what our packs weighed) and - tragically - no can opener. For some godforsaken reason we also decided to bring a swag.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/laden.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>Thankfully, the universe took one look at this disaster and set the park on fire, forcing us to turn around after the first day. We still made it to the top of Battleship Spur on our second morning, after camping halfway up because a tree had fallen on Big Bend and the whole site was fenced off. In the end, we only camped two nights and climbed up Boolimba Bluff on our way out, for a total of ~35kms, which I thought was plenty.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/rockart.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>When we made it back to civilisation, Ollie’s uncle asked him where he’d managed to find someone who would not only attempt this mission, but actually enjoy it. I think a better question might be: where did I find Ollie? &lt;3</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/sweeties.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="gracewanders"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In September 2024, Ollie and I attempted the Carnarvon Great Walk (key word: attempted).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kosciuszko</title><link href="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2024/kosci/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kosciuszko"/><published>2024-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2024/kosci</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graceponders.github.io/blog/2024/kosci/"><![CDATA[<p>My brother Luke has a healthy obsession with cutting lines in the snow, which is unfortunate because we live in Queensland. Every few years he convinces us to take the 18-hour road trip to Jindabyne for ski season, and every time I forget how cold it was last time and stupidly agree.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/troopy.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>This was Ollie’s first Smith Family Road Trip™, and I’m still surprised we didn’t scare him off. I’m also surprised that we only came home to one fine in the mail considering the number of cheese toastie makers we had running off the generator in the back of the troopy going down the M1.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/lake.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>Us-two opted out of skiing and instead hired snowshoes to hike Charlotte’s Pass to Guthega, Dead Horse Gap near Thredbo, and some of the smaller frozen lakes. It was, unsurprisingly, gruelling work, but I only ate it a handful of times, which I’m counting as a win. It was pretty special to show Ollie proper snow for the first time, and to see parts of the National Park that most people don’t make it to in winter.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/snowshoes.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>We camped in swags at our beloved Campsite 90, where we continued the family tradition of making absolute fools of ourselves in the communal kitchens while Queensland loses State of Origin. The boys took it to an entirely new level this year by stealing the fire straight out of the kitchen fireplace and dragging it back to our site in a cast iron pot. I think Ollie was officially adopted as the favourite son for participating in this heist.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/camp90.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p> <p>It was cold (so, so cold), but I couldn’t ask for better company.</p> <p>And I’m sure by the time the next trip rolls around, I’ll have convinced myself it wasn’t actually that bad.</p> <p><img src="/assets/img/blogs/ollie.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/coldgrace.jpg" style="width: 60%;"/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="gracewanders"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My brother Luke has a healthy obsession with cutting lines in the snow, which is unfortunate because we live in Queensland. Every few years he convinces us to take the 18-hour road trip to Jindabyne for ski season, and every time I forget how cold it was last time and stupidly agree.]]></summary></entry></feed>